Guide to the Records of the Institute of African American Affairs RG.9.8
New York University Archives
- Series IV. Audiovisual Recordings, 1963-2007; 50 Linear Feet in 44 record cartons, 3 card boxes, 2 cassette boxes, and 4 flat boxes.; 627 sound tape reels; 251 audiocassettes; 267 VHS; 32 Betacam; 153 U-matic; 4 DVCAM; 54 MiniDV; 1 Hi8
  - Subseries IV.B. Events Recordings, 1970-2007; 34.50 Linear Feet in 29 record cartons, 2 cassette boxes, 1 card box, and 4 flat boxes.; 267 VHS; 251 audiocassettes; 168 sound tape reels; 153 U-matic; 54 MiniDV; 32 Betacam; 4 DVCAM; 1 Hi8
    - Bamboozled Panel Discussion, 2000-11-21 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0500 -- 9-8.0505)
    - Bamboozled Panel Discussion -- Tapes 1-2, 2000-11-21 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0806 -- 9-8.0807)
    - Salif Keita Concert, 2000-11-27 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0571)
    - Salif Kaita Concert, 2000-12-07 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0808)
    - NYU Concert, 2000-12-07 (Box 65, Minidv 9-8.0646 -- 9-8.0647, 9-8.0655 -- 9-8.0661, 9-8.0666)
    - NYU Concert Camera B -- Tape 2, 2000-12-07 (Box 101, Minidv 9-8.0780 -- 9-8.0781)
    - The African Heritage Series, 2001 (Box 84, Betacam 9-8.0165)
    - Gaston Kaboré, December 2001 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0570)
    - An Evening with Malick Sidibé, 2001-10-01 (Box 80, Betacam 9-8.0138, Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0222)
    - Black Aesthetics Discussion Series: Developments in Dance, 2001-10-22 (Box 65, Minidv 9-8.0667)
    - Bamako Sigi-Kan -- Manthia Diawara, 2002 (Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0423)
    - MLA -- Walter Mosley, Colson Whitehead, and Barbara ---?, 2002 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0809)
    - Panel: "Congo: A Witness to African History", 2002-03-07 (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0224, 9-8.0243, Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0346, 9-8.0349, Box 93, Vhs 9-8.0474)
    - Africa, New York: a Discussion with Africans and African-Americans in New York, 2002-03-21 (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0232)
    - Cave Canem MFA, 2002-04-04 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0567 -- 9-8.0568)
    - Elizabeth Nuńez, 2002-04-19 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0810)
    - Lecture: Chinua Achebe, 2002-05-04 (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0247, 9-8.0250 -- 9-8.0251, Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0417 -- 9-8.0418)
    - Unknown Event -- Master Tape 1-2, 2002-05-04 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0527, 9-8.0564)
    - Maryse Conde -- Tapes 1-2, 2002-05-30 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0811 -- 9-8.0812)
    - Routes and Rootlessness: Two Jamaicans Write about the South -- Colin Channer and Kwame Dawes, 2002-07-18 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0565 -- 9-8.0566)
    - Oscar Micheaux Panel, 2002-11-04 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0569)
    - Hazel Rowley -- "Richard Wright: The Life and Times", 2002-11-15 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0813)
    - "Masking Power" -- Gerard Aching, 2002-11-20 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0814)
    - Golokwati 2000 Book Event with Kamau Braithwaite, 2002-12-11 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0574, Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0593)
    - Conakry Kas, 2003 (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0231)
    - Conakry Kas -- Rough Cut, 2003 (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0219)
    - What Next? -- Walter Mosley, 2003 (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0245 -- 9-8.0246)
    - What Next? -- Tapes 1-2, 2003-02-12 (Box 65, Minidv 9-8.0653, Box 101, Minidv 9-8.0678)
    - Africana Studies NYU -- Tapes 1-2, 2003-04-04 (Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0610 -- 9-8.0611)
    - Lecture -- Same Boat, Different Stop -- C. Daniel Dawson, 2003-04-09 (Box 93, Vhs 9-8.0461, Box 94, Vhs 9-8.0494 -- 9-8.0495, Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0606)
    - Drum Symposium 1 -- Randy Weston, circa October 2003 (Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0328, Box 93, Vhs 9-8.0482 -- 9-8.0484)
    - Drum Symposium -- Tape 1-4, circa October 2003 (Box 65, Minidv 9-8.0662 -- 9-8.0665)
    - Drums, October 2003 (Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0581)
    - Impregnable Direction -- Rush Arts Gallery, 2003-02-08 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0815)
    - Lorna Simpson (NYU), 2003-03-11 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0816)
    - Cave Canem Conversation with Michael Harper and Afaa Weaver -- Tape 1, 2003-03-13 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0817)
    - NYU Africana Studies, 2003-04-16 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0818)
    - Femi Osunla -- Brownstone, 2003-09-19 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0819)
    - Drums II, 2003-10 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0820)
    - Edwidge Danticat, 2003-10-16 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0821)
    - Ancient Future, 2003-10-21 (Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0607 -- 9-8.0608)
    - Randy Weston, 2003-10-23 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0822 -- 9-8.0823)
    - Randy Weston, 2003-10-23 (Box 65, Minidv 9-8.0648 -- 9-8.0650)
    - Randy Weston Film Screening and Conversation -- Tapes 1 -4, 2003-10-23 (Box 101, Minidv 9-8.0782 -- 9-8.0785)
    - Randy Weston -- Tape 1, 2003-10-26 (Box 101, Minidv 9-8.0786)
    - Randy Weston -- Tape 3, 2003-10-26 (Box 65, Minidv 9-8.0673)
    - Randy Weston at Skirball NYU -- #3, 2003-10-31 (Box 101, Minidv 9-8.0787)
    - Randy Weston at Skirball, 2003-10-31 (Box 65, Minidv 9-8.0668 -- 9-8.0669)
    - Randy Weston -- Final Concert, 2003-10-31 (Box 65, Minidv 9-8.0675 -- 9-8.0676, Box 101, Minidv 9-8.0677)
    - Forgotten Readers -- Elizabeth McHenry, 2003-11 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0825)
    - Unknown Event -- Tapes 1 and 2, 2003-11-07 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0575, Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0824)
    - Unknown Event -- Tape 2, 2003-11-07 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0824)
    - Unknown Event -- 4-6 PM, 2003-11-08 (Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0580, 9-8.0609)
    - Black Cinema Reconsidered: "Narrative" -- Parts I-II, 2003-11-08 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0578, Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0579)
    - Black Cinema Reconsidered: "Black Film and Popular Culture", 2003-11-08 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0576 -- 9-8.0577)
    - Hatian Writing Series -- Danielle Georges, 2003-12-03 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0826)
    - Haiti on Screen, 2004 (Box 93, Vhs 9-8.0481)
    - Haiti on Screen -- Canter Panel, 2004 (Box 91, Vhs 9-8.0376)
    - Randy Weston Lecture, 2004 (Box 91, Vhs 9-8.0378, Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0397, 9-8.0416, Box 93, Vhs 9-8.0455 -- 9-8.0459)
    - American Dilemma, 2004-02-12 (Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0582 -- 9-8.0583)
    - Dany Laferrière, 2004-02-18 (Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0588)
    - American Dilemma, 2004-02-26 (Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0586)
    - American Dilemma, 2004-03-25 (Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0584 -- 9-8.0585)
    - Haitian Film Festival -- Question and Answer, 2004-04-03 (Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0602)
    - Haitian Film Festival -- 102 Panel, 2004-04-03 (Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0600)
    - Haitian Film Festival, 2004-04-04 (Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0590, 9-8.0603)
    - Haitian Film Festival -- 2, circa 2004 (Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0595)
    - American Dilemma, 2004-04-08 (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0644 -- 9-8.0645)
    - Cave Canem -- Etienne; Paul, Haiti, 2004-04-21 (Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0604)
    - Howard French Reading, 2004-04-24 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0515)
    - Howard French Reading, 2004-04-26 (Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0591)
    - Ella Turenne's Presentation, 2004-04-28 (Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0601)
    - Exodus and Genesis: Haitian Writers in North America, 2004-04-28 (Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0589)
    - Canakry Kas -- Question and Answer, 2004-04-30 (Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0605)
    - Hugh Masekela Book Signing, 2005-02-25 (Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0592)
    - Orenny Nite Greaner, 2007-03-29 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0511)
    - Future of Mud Screening Discussion, 2007-06-20 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0516)
    - 1 VOI, undated (Box 101, Minidv 9-8.0681)
    - Abidjan Tape 4, undated (Box 79, Betacam 9-8.0130)
    - AD, April 22, undated (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0618)
    - AD, undated, April 22 (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0827)
    - Algeria -- French Colonialism, undated (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0631)
    - Ali Mazrui, undated (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0617)
    - An Evening with Walter Mosley, undated (Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0400)
    - Andrew Hill, undated; cuid15852 (Box 36, Reel cuid15852)
    - Angela Gilliam, undated; cuid15854 (Box 36, Reel cuid15854)
    - Anna Deavere Smith, undated (Box 94, U-matic 9-8.0828)
    - "Arms and the Arts" Lecture, undated (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0535)
    - Awards -- Voice-over Tags, undated (Box 84, Betacam 9-8.0149)
    - Bahia 2, undated (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0241)
    - Bamako Tapes, undated (Box 91, Vhs 9-8.0367 -- 9-8.0373)
    - Bill Greaves and Black Journals, undated (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0514)
    - Black Cinema Reconsidered, undated (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0639)
    - Black Genius, undated (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0626 -- 9-8.0627)
    - Black Horror Film, undated (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0221)
    - Black Journal 12 and 18, undated (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0255)
    - Black Studies Programs -- Parts I-II, February 27, undated; cuid15849 (Box 36, Reel cuid15849A, cuid15849B)
      Housing annotation, Pt. 1: Discussion Group A; Group Leader - Dr. Lamar Miller; Topic - "What are the Minimum Essentials that All Programs Need to Establish?"
      No. of students: 22
      No. of faculty: 12
      Housing annotation, Pt. II: Dr. King / Martin Luther King Jr. Mem.
      (1) Excerpt speech day before his death
      (2) Police Brutality
      (3) Commitment to Non-violence
      (4) Must estabish priorities
      (5) Faith in America
      (6) Entrance in Civil Rights Movement
      (7) Preacher leading his flock
      (8) Nina Simone - Why the King of Love is Dead Leader
      (9) Address to American Jewish Congress
      * The Great March to freedom * Side One * 100 years later * Segregation is wrong * Sense of dignity * Urgency of the moment * Non-violent approach
    - Blue Note -- Rahdi Taylor, undated (Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0433)
    - Brazil, undated (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0623)
    - Brother's Tin -- Taj Mabal, undated (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0629)
    - Camarade Ahmed Sékou Touré, undated (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0226)
    - The Legacy of Aimé Césaire Colloquium -- First Panel -- Robin D.G. Kelley, Edouard Glissant, Breyten Breytenbach, 2003-12-04-2003-12-06 (Box 93, Vhs 9-8.0471)
    - The Legacy of Aimé Césaire Colloquium, 2003-12-04-2003-12-06 (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0616)
    - The Legacy of Aimé Césaire Colloquium, 2003-12-04-2003-12-06 (Box 91, Vhs 9-8.0366)
    - Bill Gunn, undated (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0775)
    - Black Filmmakers Symposium -- Geoffrey Holden, Raymond St. Jacques, and Maya Angelou on "Sisters", undated (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0776)
    - Cheick Oumar Sissoko, undated (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0622, 9-8.0642)
    - Conakry Kas, undated (Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0407)
    - Maryse Condé on Aimé Césaire, undated (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0625)
    - Conversation with Yande Diop, undated (Box 91, Vhs 9-8.0374 -- 9-8.0375)
    - Dakar -- Tape 3, undated (Box 79, Betacam 9-8.0129)
    - Edwidge Danticat -- Tapes 1-2, undated (Box 65, Minidv 9-8.0651 -- 9-8.0652)
    - Derek Walcott -- Tape 1, undated (Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0405)
    - Derek Walcott -- Tape 2, undated (Box 93, Vhs 9-8.0468)
    - Discussion on Being African American in America, undated (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0547)
    - Discussion on Biography in Progress on Jazz Musician Thelonious Monk, undated (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0544)
    - Discussion on the Process of Shooting a Film in Haiti, undated (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0543)
    - Dogon Colou, undated (Box 91, Vhs 9-8.0364)
    - Dr. Brathway: Discussion of Test, undated (Box 91, Vhs 9-8.0390)
    - Du Cog a L'ame, undated (Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0302)
    - Europa, undated (Box 85, Betacam 9-8.0190)
    - "Exodus and Genisis" Fifth in Series of Lectures, undated (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0536)
    - EXTR: Ambara Dama, undated (Box 91, Vhs 9-8.0396)
    - Fatima Legrand Africana Studies, undated (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0234)
    - Festa da Yemahja, undated (Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0323)
    - Fête Chez les Hamba, undated (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0240)
    - Footage of Manthia Diawara, undated (Box 85, Betacam 9-8.0176)
    - God's Stepchild, undated (Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0356 -- 9-8.0357)
    - Guinea -- Tape 1, undated (Box 79, Betacam 9-8.0128)
    - Guinea, Maucona, Kouyate, undated (Box 80, Betacam 9-8.0133)
    - Guinea, Maucona, Mamo, Baugoura, undated (Box 80, Betacam 9-8.0136)
    - H. Diawara and Harry Belafonte Interview, undated (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0643)
    - Haiti -- #1 -- 9:30-10:30am, undated (Box 101, Minidv 9-8.0788)
    - Haiti -- #2 -- Key Note, undated (Box 101, Minidv 9-8.0789)
    - Haiti -- #3 -- Panel #1, undated (Box 101, Minidv 9-8.0790)
    - Haiti -- #4 -- Panel End, undated (Box 101, Minidv 9-8.0791)
    - Haiti -- #5-8, undated (Box 101, Minidv 9-8.0792 -- 9-8.0795)
    - Haitian Lecture, undated (Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0594)
    - Hi8mm #1, undated (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0225)
    - Hi8mm #1, undated (Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0408)
    - Hi8mm #3, undated (Box 91, Vhs 9-8.0395)
    - Hi8mm #4, undated (Box 94, Vhs 9-8.0498)
    - Hi8mm #6, undated (Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0287)
    - Hi8mm #7-9, undated (Box 94, Vhs 9-8.0497)
    - Hi8mm #8, undated (Box 94, Vhs 9-8.0499)
    - Hi8mm #9, undated (Box 94, Vhs 9-8.0496)
    - Hi8mm #14, undated (Box 91, Vhs 9-8.0392)
    - Hugh A. Hill -- NYC, undated (Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0765)
    - I Just Stopped...Grandma Jackson's Poetry, undated (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0528)
    - Illusions, undated (Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0345)
    - Interview Maya Angelo, undated (Box 84, Betacam 9-8.0144)
    - Irele, undated (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0638)
    - Ivan Dixon, undated (Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0742)
    - Jamyla -- #2, undated (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0508)
    - Jo'Berg, undated (Box 85, Betacam 9-8.0177)
    - June Jordan -- Part I-II, April 28, undated (Box 65, Minidv 9-8.0671 -- 9-8.0672)
    - Kevin Everson: Spantlelto Quantro and A Walk in the Hole, undated (Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0402)
    - L.A. Digital, undated (Box 79, Betacam 9-8.0127)
    - Larry Clark, undated (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0769)
    - Laws, Customs, Democracy, undated (Box 98, Audiocassette 9-8.0723)
    - Le Jour Ou La Guienee A Dit Non, undated (Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0333)
    - Lecture in [French?], undated (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0541)
    - Life Goes to the Movies -- Clyde Taylor, undated (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0244)
    - Lisa Stefanoff -- "Saxophonelisa", undated (Box 91, Vhs 9-8.0389)
    - Manthia Diawara -- 16x9, undated (Box 79, Betacam 9-8.0126)
    - Matt's Washington Square Park, undated (Box 85, U-matic 9-8.0180)
    - Moskowitz Lecture -- Reels 1-2, undated; cuid15848 (Box 36, Reel cuid15848A, cuid15848B)
      Housing annotation, Reel 1: Prof. Jan Tinbergen. Mainstream. Karen Vest - Harlem Renaissance.
    - Oscar Micheaux Movie -- Ten Minutes to Live, undated (Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0424)
    - Michel Fabre, undated (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0619)
    - More at Goree, undated (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0223)
    - Morning -- Tape 1, undated (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0630)
    - Nambikwara -- Peche, undated (Box 91, Vhs 9-8.0387)
    - National Rosacea Society VNR and B--Roll, undated (Box 91, Betacam 9-8.0363)
    - Nature of Freedom, undated (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0615)
    - Night Party, undated (Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0334)
    - No a la France, undated (Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0327)
    - Patterns #1 -- NYU IAAA, undated; cuid15850 (Box 36, Reel cuid15850)
    - Patterns #2 -- Publishing Force, undated; cuid15851 (Box 36, Reel cuid15851)
      Housing annotations: "Producer: Lynn Sharpe"
    - Patterns #3 -- Black Vote Power, undated; cuid15853 (Box 36, Reel cuid15853)
    - Patterns #4 -- Black Politicians Why, undated; cuid15855 (Box 36, Reel cuid15855)
      The tape's housing annotations suggest sensitive content and the use of derogatory language.
    - Patterns #8 -- Johnson Publications, undated; cuid15856 (Box 36, Reel cuid15856)
    - Patterns #11 -- Black Authors, undated; cuid15857 (Box 36, Reel cuid15857)
    - Patterns #12 -- Black Theatre, undated; cuid15860 (Box 36, Reel cuid15860)
    - Patterns #13 -- Black Student Unions, undated; cuid15861 (Box 36, Reel cuid15861)
    - Patterns #14 -- Open Admissions, undated; cuid15862 (Box 36, Reel cuid15862)
    - Patterns #17 and #18 -- Adventures Through Afro-American Music, undated; cuid15863 (Box 36, Reel cuid15863A, cuid15863B)
    - Patterns #19 -- Tribute to Malcolm X, undated; cuid15865 (Box 36, Reel cuid15865)
    - Pearl Bowser, undated (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0772)
    - Professor Winks, 20th Century Afro--American Literature -- Carolyn J. Goldman, undated (Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0598)
    - Radhi as First Witch in Macbeth, undated (Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0415)
    - Randy Weston Tea and Conversation Africana, undated (Box 65, Minidv 9-8.0674, Box 101, Minidv 9-8.0679 -- 9-8.0680)
    - Research Adjuvant, undated (Box 91, Vhs 9-8.0393)
    - River -- After Tape 2, undated (Box 91, Vhs 9-8.0361)
    - Robert C. Banks Jr. Preview Screener, undated (Box 94, Vhs 9-8.0830)
    - Ron La Porte's Music Phone, undated (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0620)
    - Rosa Guy, undated (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0624)
    - Salvador -- Tape 1, undated (Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0406)
    - Seuegal: Interview and Street Scenes, undated (Box 85, Betacam 9-8.0189)
    - Seydou Traore Suite Salif Keita, undated (Box 65, Minidv 9-8.0654)
    - Sidime Laye and Sekou Toure Tapes Guinea 1, 2, undated (Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0343)
    - Spike Lee -- Lecture, undated (Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0291)
    - Stolen Moments, undated (Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0403)
    - Straight Black Studies, undated (Box 94, Vhs 9-8.0488)
    - Tape 1 of 1, undated (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0637)
    - The River Nige, undated (Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0411)
    - Terry McMillan, undated (Box 89, Audiocassette 9-8.0596)
    - The Train Catches Fire, undated (Box 91, Vhs 9-8.0384)
    - Third World Newsreel 35 Years of Progressive Media Panel Clips, undated (Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0286)
    - Trains Around Bamaka, undated (Box 91, Vhs 9-8.0394)
    - TWF/V -- Pearl -- Kalainu(?) -- Acklyn, undated (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0766)
    - Unblinking Eye: NYU Poetry, undated (Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0303)
    - "The Black Athlete's Responsibility to the Black Community," a presentation by Cal Ramsey and Tom Sanders, undated; cuid17298 (Box 39, Reel cuid17298A, cuid17298B, cuid17298C)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0230)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0233)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 90, Vhs 9-8.0353)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-8.0513)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 87, Vhs 9-8.0239)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 88, Vhs 9-8.0284)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 85, Betacam 9-8.0186)
    - Van Sertima -- Morning, undated (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0636)
    - Wu-Tang, undated (Box 97, Audiocassette 9-8.0640)
    - You Dig It. Epitaph; Richie Mason's Last Film, undated (Box 64, Audiocassette 9-8.0767)
    - Youssou N'Dour, undated (Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0413)
    - Youssou N'Dour Studio: Shopping in a Shoes Store and Meeting with Aminata Traore, undated (Box 92, Vhs 9-8.0412)
  - Subseries IV.C. Pre-Institute Recordings, 1963-1968; 9 Linear Feet in 9 record cartons.; 193 sound tape reels
    This subseries contains audio recordings created prior to the formation of the Institute of African American Affairs (IAAA) in 1969. This subseries includes audio recordings of the May 1965 Teach-In at NYU, featuring IAAA Founding Director Dr. Roscoe C. Brown Jr.
    This subseries also includes the 1963 to 1967 audio recordings from The Urban League Presents, a recurring radio show produced by the Communication Arts Group of New York University for the Urban League of Greater New York. Episode content reflects this organization's mission as a nonpartisan historic civil rights organization that advocates on behalf of economic and social justice for African Americans and against racial discrimination in the United States. These recordings were broadcast initially on other stations and rebroadcast on WNYU. Earlier episodes dating from 1959 to 1962 are available in the University Archives Audiovisual Collection (AV).
    - Teach-In -- Reel 1, 1965-05-05; RG9-8_ref4426; 1 sound tape reels (Box 39)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
      Format: 1/4 inch open reel audio tape
    - Teach-In -- Reel 2, 1965-05-05; cuid15834; 1 sound tape reels (Box 39)
    - Teach-In -- Reel 3, 1965-05-05; cuid15835; 1 sound tape reels (Box 39)
    - Teach-In -- Reel 4, 1965-05-05; cuid15836; 1 sound tape reels (Box 39)
    - Teach-In -- Reel 5, 1965-05-05; cuid15837; 1 sound tape reels (Box 39)
    - Teach-In -- Reel 6, 1965-05-05; cuid15838; 1 sound tape reels (Box 39)
    - Teach-In -- Reel 7, 1965-05-05; cuid15839; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 39)
    - Teach-In -- Reel 8, 1965-05-05; cuid15840; 1 sound tape reels (Box 39)
    - Teach-In -- Reel 9, 1965-05-05; cuid15841; 1 sound tape reels (Box 39)
    - Teach-In -- Reel 10, 1965-05-05; cuid15842; 1 sound tape reels (Box 39)
    - Teach-In -- Reel 11, 1965-05-05; cuid15843; 1 sound tape reels (Box 39)
    - The Urban League Presents: The Desegregated Heart, Part II, 1963-01-13 (Box 44, Reel 9-8.0868)
    - The Urban League Presents: Should New York Abolish the Death Penalty?, Part I, 1963-01-27 (Box 44, Reel 9-8.0869)
    - The Urban League Presents: Should New York Abolish the Death Penalty?, Part II, 1963-02-03 (Box 44, Reel 9-8.0870)
    - The Urban League Presents: Neighborhood Study Clubs, 1963-02-18; cuid17293 (Box 42, Reel cuid17293)
    - The Urban League Presents: Neighborhood Study Clubs, 1963-02-24; cuid17294 (Box 42, Reel cuid17294)
    - The Urban League Presents: Is Queens a Gilded Ghetto?, 1963-03-03 (Box 43, Reel 9-8.0831)
    - The Urban League Presents: Freedom Task Force, 1963-03-10 (Box 43, Reel 9-8.0832)
    - The Urban League Presents: New Consumer Protection for Housewives, Part II, 1963-05-05 (Box 43, Reel 9-8.0833)
    - The Urban League Presents Has Negro Leadership By-Passed the Bronx, Part I, 1963-05-19 (Box 48, Reel 9-8.0976)
    - The Urban League Presents: Has Negro Leadership By-Passed the Bronx, Part II, 1963-05-26 (Box 43, Reel 9-8.0834)
    - The Urban League Presents: Brooklyn's Growing Unemployment, 1963-06-02 (Box 43, Reel 9-8.0835)
    - The Urban League Presents: Mobilization for Youth, Part I, 1963-06-09 (Box 48, Reel 9-8.0977)
    - The Urban League Presents: Mobilization for Youth, Part II, 1963-06-16 (Box 48, Reel 9-8.0978)
    - The Urban League Presents: Negro Image on TV, 1963-06-23 (Box 48, Reel 9-8.0979)
    - The Urban League Presents: A White Lawyer Leaves Mississippi, Part I, 1963-06-30 (Box 48, Reel 9-8.0980)
    - The Urban League Presents: A White Lawyer Leaves Mississippi -- Part II, 1963-07-07; cuid17288 (Box 42, Reel cuid17288)
    - The Urban League Presents: Race and Poverty -- Part II, 1963-07-28; cuid17297 (Box 42, Reel cuid17297)
    - The Urban League Presents: JFK's Equal Employment Opportunities Committee -- Part I, 1963-08-04; cuid17295 (Box 42, Reel cuid17295)
    - The Urban League Presents: JFK's Equal Employment Opportunities Committee -- Part II, 1963-08-11; cuid17296 (Box 42, Reel cuid17296)
    - The Urban League Presents: New Consumer Protection for Housewives, 1963-09-01 (Box 43, Reel 9-8.0836)
    - The Urban League Presents: Are Race Labels Ever Justified, 1963-09-09 (Box 44, Reel 9-8.0871)
    - The Urban League Presents: A New Look for Harlem, 1963-09-22 (Box 43, Reel 9-8.0837)
    - The Urban League Presents: A New Way to Crack Job Bias, 1963-09-29 (Box 44, Reel 9-8.0872)
    - The Urban League Presents: Rent Control and You -- Part II, 1963-12-15; cuid17315 (Box 47, Reel cuid17315)
    - Urban League Christmas Show, 1963-12-22; cuid17291 (Box 42, Reel cuid17291)
    - The Urban League Presents: Medical Care for the Retired Worker, 1963-12-29 (Box 43, Reel 9-8.0838)
    - The Urban League Presents: The Need for a Negro Labor Alliance, Part I, 1964-01-05 (Box 44, Reel 9-8.0873)
    - The Urban League Presents: The Need for a Negro Labor Alliance, Part II, 1964-01-12 (Box 44, Reel 9-8.0874)
    - The Urban League Presents: A School Integration Report, Part II, 1964-01-26 (Box 44, Reel 9-8.0875)